<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tidyverse on Exploring Data</title>
    <link>/tags/tidyverse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tidyverse on Exploring Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tidyverse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tips for Data Cleaning in R</title>
      <link>/post/quick-tips-for-data-cleaning-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/quick-tips-for-data-cleaning-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Data Cleaning (istockphoto)
 What to Expect I’m excited to share pro-tips that will expedite your process for cleaning and standardizing column names in your data; this is a critical yet sometimes overlooked step in the cleaning + tidying of data.
There are a couple of handy functions() available in R to help effectively execute these tasks.
By the end of this short article you’ll have a couple of new tricks up your sleeve for getting those column names just the way you want them 😎</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining Data with glimpse()</title>
      <link>/post/examining-data-with-glimpse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/examining-data-with-glimpse/</guid>
      <description>Let’s Dive into an Example I’m a nerd 🤓 when it comes to programming (esp. in R) and love learning about new functions.
Matt Dancho, early in his Data Science Foundations with R Course, teaches students the importance of examining data before diving into wrangling and exploring it further.
One of the functions I’ve adopted from the course is the glimpse() function - it’s awesome and I use it all the time!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Plots with str_glue()</title>
      <link>/post/advanced-plots-in-r-with-str_glue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/advanced-plots-in-r-with-str_glue/</guid>
      <description>Enter your Email Here to receive notifications when new content is posted.
Let’s Dive Into an Example I’d like to share a technique using str_glue() that I learned from Matt Dancho, a Data-Science instructor at Business Science University. Check out my favorite course here: Business Analysis With R.
str_glue() from the stringr library is one of my favorite functions in R - It’s super helpful for wrangling and manipulating text in preparation for building advanced plots.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>