<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Exploring Data</title>
    <link>https://www.exploringdata.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Exploring Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.exploringdata.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R Packages: {janitor} for Data Cleaning</title>
      <link>https://www.exploringdata.org/post/r-packages-janitor-for-data-cleaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.exploringdata.org/post/r-packages-janitor-for-data-cleaning/</guid>
      <description>Github Page as of 8/10/20
 Quick Overview Exploring-Data is a place where I share easily digestible content aimed at making the wrangling and exploration of data more efficient (+fun).
Sign up Here to join the many other subscribers who also nerd out on new tips and tricks 🤓
And if you enjoy the post be sure to share it
Tweet   New Series: Exploring R {packages} When I discover new and helpful functions I light up 💡 with excitement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Data Analysis Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.exploringdata.org/post/exploratory-data-analysis-eda-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.exploringdata.org/post/exploratory-data-analysis-eda-guide/</guid>
      <description>Quick Overview Hadley Wickham and Garrett Grolemund wrote an incredible book called R for Data Science (R4DS). In the book they teach how to “turn raw data into understanding, insight, and knowledge.” The authors do this by being laser focused on the tools that help the data-practitioner import, tidy, transform, visualize, and model data (+communicate findings):
R4DS Workflow
 I dug into the chapter on Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) this past week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tips for Data Cleaning in R</title>
      <link>https://www.exploringdata.org/post/quick-tips-for-data-cleaning-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.exploringdata.org/post/quick-tips-for-data-cleaning-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Data Cleaning (istockphoto)
 What to Expect I’m excited to share pro-tips that will expedite your process for cleaning and standardizing column names in your data; this is a critical yet sometimes overlooked step in the cleaning + tidying of data.
There are a couple of handy functions() available in R to help effectively execute these tasks.
By the end of this short article you’ll have a couple of new tricks up your sleeve for getting those column names just the way you want them 😎</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Ready Plots with R</title>
      <link>https://www.exploringdata.org/post/business-ready-plots-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.exploringdata.org/post/business-ready-plots-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Quick Overview Recently, I completed the Data Science for Business 101 course over at Business Science University. In the course, Matt Dancho teaches students the fundamentals of data science for business with the tidyverse.
The course is jam packed with material: from basic data wrangling all the way to applied machine learning - I highly recommend it to anyone looking to advance their skills 🤓
Clink this LINK to access the course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining Data with glimpse()</title>
      <link>https://www.exploringdata.org/post/examining-data-with-glimpse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.exploringdata.org/post/examining-data-with-glimpse/</guid>
      <description>Let’s Dive into an Example I’m a nerd 🤓 when it comes to programming (esp. in R) and love learning about new functions.
Matt Dancho, early in his Data Science Foundations with R Course, teaches students the importance of examining data before diving into wrangling and exploring it further.
One of the functions I’ve adopted from the course is the glimpse() function - it’s awesome and I use it all the time!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Plots with str_glue()</title>
      <link>https://www.exploringdata.org/post/advanced-plots-in-r-with-str_glue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.exploringdata.org/post/advanced-plots-in-r-with-str_glue/</guid>
      <description>Source: https://bit.ly/2CGyS6I
 Enter your Email Here to get the latest from Exploring-Data in your inbox.
Let’s Dive Into an Example I’d like to share a technique using str_glue() that I learned from Matt Dancho, a Data-Science instructor at Business Science University. Check out my favorite course here: Business Analysis With R.
str_glue() from the stringr library is one of my favorite functions in R - It’s super helpful for wrangling and manipulating text in preparation for building advanced plots.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>